<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>鏡は悟りの具ならず、迷いの具なり。</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2016-05-18T23:24:35-07:00</updated><entry><title>Data Visualization Projet</title><link href="/data-visualization-projet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-18T23:24:35-07:00</published><author><name>fooloo</name></author><id>tag:,2016-05-18:data-visualization-projet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This visualization shows UC Berkeley Fall semester enrollment by gender and ethnicity since 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demo: &lt;a href="http://sandbox.runjs.cn/show/z9r4xhdv"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Data Science"></category><category term="Javascript"></category><category term="Data"></category><category term="Data Visualization"></category><category term="D3Js"></category></entry><entry><title>Identities are Projections of a High-dimensional Object on a Low-dimensional World</title><link href="/identities-are-projections-of-a-high-dimensional-object-on-a-low-dimensional-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-28T16:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>fooloo</name></author><id>tag:,2014-11-24:identities-are-projections-of-a-high-dimensional-object-on-a-low-dimensional-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="nontext"&gt;
&lt;img class="blogimg" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.timnobleandsuewebster.com/tnsw_works/2010_self_imposed_misery/self_imposed_misery.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="nontext-caption"&gt;SELF IMPOSED MISERY, 2010 - &lt;a href="www.timnobleandsuewebster.com/"&gt;Tim Noble &amp; Sue Webster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to run a nonprofit art forum, which at its prime had over 20 thousand users and 2 thousand new posts per day. At first, I thought a lot about how to be a good admin—both a friend of users and a respectable trust-worthy organizer. Following my intuition, I tried to construct this image in my mind: To avoid prejudice, his language and behavior obscure his gender, though in the profile it shows male. At that time, there was a stereotype of girls on the Internet—indecisive and petulant; for this reason many girls don’t want to reveal their gender online. That would make it hard to build up authority, I thought. I further decided he is a 17- or 18-year-old young man with a warm smile; he is nice, easygoing, calm, gentle and capable of settling any conflict, taking care of almost everything. I designed this character to soften people’s feeling. The interesting thing is, I realize now, rather than a virtual persona, he is more like a character in my fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="nontext"&gt;
&lt;img class="blogimg" src="https://yaqim.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/hei.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="nontext-caption"&gt;The image I used for profile picture (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darker_than_Black"&gt;Darker than Black&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With painstaking planning, I put a picture of the hero of a popular animation at that time—also a young man whom I believe has likable personality. One thing you need to notice is that, in the same picture, there is also a black cat at the position as important as that of the hero in the composition. My online id was Mr. Cat. Therefore if you first know my id and then look at my picture, the image of the cat and personality of the hero are integrated into your perception of my identity. At least that was what I had expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The information loss of online communication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be wondering why people appear to be different on the Internet. Let’s start thinking how we get information about others through Internet. If we want to know someone on the Internet, how do we know about others? The answer is observation: By observation, people get information from sight, from everything that we can see on the Internet. When we wear sunglasses, less light comes into our eyes. So is it with Internet—another kind of sunglasses; it is a filter that only those voluntarily transmitted, numerical data can pass through. That means information other than those are lost, for example the scents, or even the physical presence. We learn about someone through a channel where most of the information types cannot pass through. Therefore we can say gaining information is always accompanied by losing other information; observation is always accompanied by overlooking. We can see others, but we cannot “hear” what they want to “say”. With the loss of information that people intend to conveyed, Internet is probably never an adequate media to really know someone, or even to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the human factors that make online identity turn out to be misleading?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason comes from two aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you played with hand shadow? What does it say about your hands? Does the rabbit shadow on the wall mean that your hand is rabbit-shaped?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="nontext"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DBJrZYmK_UA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class="nontext-caption"&gt;A great work of hand shadow that I found on youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course not. Hand shadows are funny and interesting, but how about our identity, the shadow of personality? If creating an identity is just like creating a shadow with hands, I think people are fond of this creation: As I mentioned earlier, the experience of constructing an online persona is similar to creating a character in the fiction. As long as textual message is still the foundation and mainstream of online experience, it blurs the line between reality and fiction. Moreover, it is nature that people want acceptance and appreciation from others. We want to display our good sides, and, if given a chance, we also want to become ideal selves in the world of conceived reality. The major problem is that unlike what happens in real world, Internet let us describe ourselves but our descriptions are subjective. Life is crude but what happens on the Internet is pre-processed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, incomplete information leads to incomplete cognition. With limited information, people tend to imagine beyond what they see: Behind something good must be all good things and vice versa, just like our brains fill the blind spot in our visual field with imagined information. When we look at a projection, we unconsciously imagine what the object is like on the basis of the silhouette. However what we see cannot fill the blank that we do not see. With incomplete information, we can’t see the truth about others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="non-text"&gt;
&lt;embed height="415" width="544" quality="high" allowfullscreen="true" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://static.hdslb.com/miniloader.swf" flashvars="aid=706&amp;page=1" pluginspage="http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;p class="nontext-caption"&gt;Anime music movie “Bad Apple!!” using 3D silhouette in the transition of shots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do online identities have to do with our personalities?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our identities, including those on the Internet, are projections of a high-dimensional object on a low-dimensional world. As a complicated creature, human is a high-dimensional object, with itself being a bundle of massive information. Our system of standards in a specific situation is a low dimensional world. Based on it, our perception of others only shows one aspect of the information. The differences between what our personalities are and what other people see about them might be due to people tend to see things in the different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the value is a functional that maps things, which are high-dimensional in nature, to one-dimensional world. When people deal with complicated things, it is an instinct for people to evaluate them to get an order relation. In this process, people of different values use different functions, which lead to totally different results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this from the blog (&lt;a href="https://www.byvoid.com/en/"&gt;BYVoid&lt;/a&gt;) of a Chinese student from Tsinghua University. In this passage, &lt;a href="https://www.byvoid.com/zhs/blog/high-dimensional-world-and-unified-value"&gt;High-dimensional World and Unified Value&lt;/a&gt;, he writes about super computers and computation about values in everyday life. I think this idea of computation can also be extended to the relationship between our personalities and online identities. It is a very cautious point of view he raises to compare the process to a function without defining it. However, as far as I am concerned, a more intuitive apperception of this process is assimilating them to a projection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than a one-dimensional value, Internet sifts the information by limiting the form of information that can be transmitted and seemingly neutrally presents it (because people writes them bias them beforehand). Internet allows people to live in a low-dimensional world. On the Internet, we are used to seeing an incomplete images of others’ personalities, thereby we can rarely fully understand their personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Internet values?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were first born in this world, we do not have values. We obtain our values through living with others. We learn from our projections in adults’ eye and we use the same standards to shape and rule our own personalities. Then they become our values. Values are the scale of the low-dimensional worlds of our cognitions; they are the celebrated property or qualities. Our values accumulate and change with our experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet is also such a low-dimensional world, but the question is what is its standard? The Internet values are those values that we absorb from our experience on the Internet. How does those values affect us in the real world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to comment and tell me what you think about this question.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Writing"></category><category term="Online Identity"></category><category term="Internet Introspection"></category><category term="Identity"></category></entry><entry><title>Recent Sketch</title><link href="/recent-sketch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-06T06:04:43-08:00</published><author><name>fooloo</name></author><id>tag:,2014-11-06:recent-sketch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt" src="https://yaqim.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/141011.jpg?w=1024" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too lazy to finish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_(:3J L)_&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Drawing"></category><category term="Original"></category></entry><entry><title>Mirroring of Mother and Daughter: The Long Journey to Independence in Annie John</title><link href="/mirroring-of-mother-and-daughter-the-long-journey-to-independence-in-annie-john.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-06T05:42:48-08:00</published><author><name>fooloo</name></author><id>tag:,2014-11-06:mirroring-of-mother-and-daughter-the-long-journey-to-independence-in-annie-john.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="nontext"&gt;
&lt;img class="blogimg" src="https://yaqim.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/386336.jpg?w=201&amp;h=300" /&gt;
&lt;p class="nontext-caption"&gt;Cover - Annie John, by Jamaica Kincaid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first person narrative novel, Annie John, by Jamaica Kincaid, recounts coming of age stories of Annie John. In this novel, Kincaid demonstrates the themes of mother-and-daughter relationship and self-identity. Throughout Kincaid’s narration, it is a remarkable fact that Annie and her mother, whose influence comes from years of proximity, are so much alike: Apart from her physical traits—such as her intelligence and appearance—inherited from her mother, she also picks upon her mother’s mannerisms. Moreover, her identity is wrapped up with how she spends her childhood and adolescence with her mother. Once when Annie quarrels with her mother, she says to her mother, “Well, like father like son, like mother like daughter” (102). This notion suggests a mirroring relationship between daughter and mother that is, at one point, adorable intimacy, while later in her life becomes a burden in defining herself. Realizing the lack of originality in her identity because of copying her mother, she finally makes the decision to leave her family and homeland where she was born and raised up for England to seek a new life. While inevitably mirroring her mother, Annie realizes her selfhood and grows from a lamb tied to her mother’s apron strings to an independent female rebelliously striving to find her own identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annie’s imitation of her mother reflects that her perception of herself is influenced by her mother. For example, before twelve, Annie enjoys being a mini version of her mother by matching her mother’s dressing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to then, my mother and I had many dresses made out of the same cloth, though hers had a different, more grownup style, a boat neck or a sweetheart neckline, and a pleated or gored skirt, while my dresses had high necks with collars, a deep hemline, and, of course, a sash that tied in the back. One day, my mother and I had gone to get some material for new dresses to celebrate her birthday (the usual gift from my father), when I came upon a piece of cloth—a yellow background, with figures of men, dressed in a long-ago fashion, seated at pianos that they were playing, and all around them musical notes flying off into the air. I immediately said how much I loved this piece of cloth, but my mother replied, “Oh, no. You are getting too old for that. It’s time you had your own clothes. You just cannot go around the rest of your life looking like a little me.”…In the end, I got my dress with the men playing their pianos, and my mother got a dress with red and yellow overgrown hibiscus. (25-26)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she was young and naïve, Annie and her mother used to wear clothes “cut from the same cloth”—a phrase is not only referring to the material of their clothes, but implying that Annie shares a lot of similarities with her mother. Furthermore, their similarity is from the connection between the two who were once a unity: Like a small piece of cloth cut from a large one, so was Annie, an infant, cut from her mother’s body after delivery. Annie cognize herself as not her own being, but part of her mother, whom she can relies on and who gives her personality and sense of security while she doesn’t have her individual personality and security from being herself. Through idiom and symbolism, Kincaid suggests the motive of Annie’s imitation that makes her and her mother similar is Annie’s rooted misconception about self-identity that she is affiliated with her mother rather than as a separate individual. This misconception attributed to her dependent personality impedes the development of her own identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this union of mother and daughter is negated when Annie’s mother suddenly refuses to have Annie wear like herself. Therefore Annie shows nostalgia in demand of the affinity and union that she has been used to. Her fondness for element of “long-ago fashion” in the pattern she chooses shows her nostalgia for her childhood. This sentiment is confirmed when she continues to recount, “a few days earlier I had asked in my most pleasing, winning way for a look through the trunk” (27) which stores memorials from her childhood; she misses the past time when she used to look through the trunk with her mother and watch her mother as being told a story that happened long ago about one of the collections. Feeling the bitterness for the refusal and alienation from her mother because of the changes taking place in her body during adolescence, Annie wishes she “could screw [her]self at night before [she] went to sleep and which would surely cut back on [her] growing” (27). She is fixated in the past. She longs to be the little child again—even if this means torturing herself—to retrieve her mother’s support and cares. Nonetheless she doesn’t want to conform the young-lady business as her mother wished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patterns that mother and daughter choose also reflect their characters respectively, the contradiction of which explains the reason for their conflicts: Annie appreciates the pattern of “notes flying off into the air”—an imagery of freedom. Interestingly, the mother takes “a dress with red and yellow overgrown hibiscus” which is considered a symbol of delicate beauty. Similarly, her taste for the style of her dresses—“a boat neck or a sweetheart neckline, and a pleated or gored skirt”—highlights very female, elegant and captivating features. Annie’s mother celebrates feminine charms, decency and elegant manners and instill her sense of value to Annie as well, which explains why she fixates on making sure Annie behaves like a proper young lady. However, to Annie, practicing young-lady business is restricting her freedom. When she is sent for piano lessons, Annie is asked “not to come back” by her piano teacher for she is “unable to resist eating from the bowl of plums she had placed on the piano purely for decoration” (28). Her unruly behavior shows her antipathy against following rules. Even though she enjoys being a mini version of her mother, she resists her mother’s restraint. This unruliness becomes the embryo of her later rebelliousness and ego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unable to count on her mother anymore, Annie also loses the sense of security and suddenly she is exposed to the inverse of it—crisis. In response to the change of her mother’s attitude, Annie attempts to protect herself in a way that she intentionally imitates her mother’s tone to reciprocate the abominable tone her mother uses. One time she doesn’t go back home right after school and her mother comes to her for the reason of being late:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me she said, “You are late. It would please me to hear an excuse from you.” She was using that tone of voice: it was as if I were not only a stranger but a stranger that she did not wish to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to match her tone of voice but coming nowhere near success, I said something about being kept late for extra studies. (101)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She doesn’t want to tell the truth for she knows that her mother will scold her for that. To defend herself, she matches her mother’s tone and tells a lie. Another time when her mother asks in a way that Annie finds hypocritical for the marbles that Annie hides, she echoes her mother’s hypocrisy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, Little Miss, where are your marbles?” Summoning my own warm, soft and newly acquired treacherous voice, I said, “I don’t have any marbles. I have never played marbles, you know.” (70)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In imitating the voice of her mother, Annie also shows her strong sense of defending herself. Without the person she can depend upon, Annie sinks in the feeling that she is abandoned in a cold and dangerous world, and her mother, in turn, plays a hypocritical role in front of her. This grieves Annie. In demand of self-assurance and protection from her mother’s stinging attitude, she immediately reciprocates her mother the same hypocrisy. She forms an unyielding personality and develops a pattern of rebellion that she will throw back whatever she thinks hurt her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it is ironic that as Annie rebels her mother, she is also influenced by her mother. Influenced her mother’s aesthetic, her appearance reminds readers of her mother at youth. They are both thin and inclined to hide their faces. Annie so described her mother:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He back was already curved from not ever stand up straight, even though she got repeated warnings. She was so shy that she never smiled enough for you to see her teeth, and if she ever burst out laughing she would instantly cover her mouth with her hands. (69)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a description of Annie herself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking to and from school, my long-skirt uniform hanging on my thin form, my head held down, my back curved in an exaggerated stoop, one arm held behind me and resting on my lower back, the other anchoring the bag that held my books, each step I took purposely timid, I created such a picture that apparently everyone talked about me. (128)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, mother and daughter give people the same impression of introversion—they look shy and timid. Because of her new height, Annie has to stoop, which also resembles her mother. She wears shorter skirt and acts timidly and modestly. These feminine characteristics mirror her mother’s aesthetic conception as a result of instillation of her mother’s values as a woman to Annie. Notwithstanding, Annie does these intentionally and she is totally different from her look. She is not modest but achieving a figure that seems modest in order to impress others. Her pursuit for others’ attention shows her gradually formation of self-consciousness, which is significant for Annie to get rid of her dependent personality and to identify herself as her own being. Though she tries to be distinct from her mother, ironically, Annie develop her own personality through doing things that her mother did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the figurative characterization of mother and daughter hints the mirroring of the two. For example, black things that hail from their insides is a motif, “My mother turned to face me. We looked at each other, and I could see the frightening black thing leave her to meet the frightening black thing that had left me. They met in the middle and embraced…At that, everything stopped. The whole earth fell silent. The two black things joined together in the middle of the room separated, hers going to her, mine coming back to me…” (101,102). The phrases “in the middle”, “in the middle of the room”, the characterization of black things assumes symmetry in the scenes as if there is a mirror placed between them. The black substance exclusively observed by mother and daughter is a paradoxical trope for it symbolizes two extremes in their relationship: “Embrace” suggests accepting each other willingly. Though the mother and the daughter might have not noticed, they are attracting each other because they are so much alike. However contradictorily, what embraces seems not so nice. The black thing also indicates the secret antagonism of the two, which is what their relationship seems like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another suggestive instance of their mirroring relationship is their name. The name of Annie’s mother is not disclosed until the last few chapters. “She was my mother, Annie; I was her daughter, Annie” (105)—the same name. Why do Annie’s parents give her the name of her mother? Usually giving one a name after another means a memorial of the latter or an expectation that the former will become a person like the latter. The name qualifies the person. “[T]he person who receives a name thereby receives an identity and a place within the society”, as H. Edward Deluzain asserts in Names and Personal Identity. “The name differentiates the child from others; thus, the society will be able to treat and deal with the child as someone with needs and feelings different from those of other people.” Annie grows up with a name bestowing the identity of her mother, while her own needs and feelings are overlooked by her parents and society. Yet Annie realizes that she is different and seeks her own identity, transcending her mother’s influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending of the novel is ironic; Annie leaves her mother and seems to have found a brand new life—in a strange place with no one knows her, yet that was also what her mother did. In some ways, Annie doesn’t get away from the cycle of fate—these two generations ultimately go on the same route. Her mother’s experience repeats in the daughter’s coming-of-age. However, Annie does acquire her own perceptions and personalities: Her own rebellion against marriage and unyielding character are especially prodigious in this social background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Annie, we find an image of a youngster that may relate to ourselves, an image that misgives, loves, grieves and grows. We frequently ask who we are and what kind of people we will be. Like Annie, most of the time we do something because we feel that we have to do and we have to change. In exploring her own identity, Annie, beginning with a dependent personality, achieves independence of character. Though through one time or two of efforts we might not be able to convert us into our ideal selves, we are always getting closer and closer in continuous pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Works Cited&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kincaid, Jamaica. &lt;em&gt;Annie John&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Penguin, 1986. Print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deluzain, H. Edward. “Names and Personal Identity.” &lt;em&gt;Behind the Name&lt;/em&gt;. 1996. Web. 20 Apr. 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Annie John"></category><category term="Coming-of-Age"></category><category term="Jamaica"></category><category term="Kincaid"></category><category term="Literary Analysis"></category><category term="Writing Practice"></category></entry><entry><title>Before the Performance</title><link href="/before-the-performance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-06T05:24:49-08:00</published><author><name>fooloo</name></author><id>tag:,2014-11-06:before-the-performance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;“I’ll be on the stage tomorrow.” I rush to my mom as soon as I see her. “Our group is going to dance in the Children’s Day performance, in front of everyone! Parents can come too. You will come and watch me dance, won’t you?” I guess she knows I am not really asking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m so proud of you!” she hugs me and picks me up. I reach my arms around her neck so that I can sniff the delightful and comforting fragrance of mom in her embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I will be there,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we step into the house together. The happiest moment of my life is coming—my mom is going to watch me dance! The rich perfume of sweet osmanthus from the garden mixed with the familiar odor of home-style cooking intoxicate me. Everything seems more enjoyable just because you know something good is coming soon for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;*                 *                 *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Chen, our teacher and director of performance, has applied makeup for the last one of us. It won’t be long before we take the stage. My heart can’t help bouncing hard in my chest and all the blood comes rushing to my head. There is no way for me to calm down. Stealthily tilting my head to the mirror and pretending to pass by, I assure myself that the heat on my face is not noticeable thanks to Ms. Chen’s perfect makeup—cherry lips, apple cheeks, bright round eyes with naturally long eyelashes. Hopping forward and backward in an appreciation of the costume, I feel something inside is booming and about to burst into light and heat. I am dressed in a cute snowy skirt since I will play the little white bunny—one of the main roles in this performance. On my head is a furry bunny ear hairband, which I can’t stop touching. When the other girls call “Little white bunny, please come here and help us pull out the carrot”. I am to jump out from the backstage and join them. I have practiced the dance and lines at home and had several rehearsals so I will not make any mistakes. What’s more, my mom will come to watch me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To kill some time, I hang around the backstage to see what my partner, other two leading dancer, in our group are doing. At one side of the stage, Jin, who along with Tong plays the grey bunny sisters, is waving to her mother in the audience, giggling. Obviously, she is nervous. I give her a nudge and say, “Jin, do you see my mom?” As expected, I am ignored. Tong’s mother volunteers to apply makeup to performers so Tong can stay by her side. Watching them chat about the pending performance really makes people jealous. I don’t want to join their conversation. I need to find my mom before our dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaning out of the stage curtain and searching for my mom in the crowds over and over again, I find nothing but disappointment. “It’s okay. I won’t blame her for being late,” I murmur to myself. She is definitely coming and there is a while before we start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Girls in Class A, attention please!” says Ms. Chen. Hearing her voice, I stop searching and turn to her as everyone else does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are going to perform soon, so I need you to gather here now. Be confident and show your best,” Ms. Chen continues to say. Then she sees me and walks towards me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you okay, honey? What’s wrong with you?” Ms. Chen goes down to her knee to hold my hand and asks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What? Why do I have to perform now? I thought my show time would be later.” What’s wrong with me? Looking into her eyes, I see my own bewildered reflection, “Do you see my mom?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry, honey. I haven’t because, you see, I have been staying here with you.” Ms. Chen gently touches my nervously clenched fist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I won’t dance unless she comes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I won’t, I decide. It’s all meaningless if she isn’t watching. I have to buy time, as much as I can until she arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t see her but she’s probably in the audience. Come on, she’ll see you on the stage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No! If she is here she will come to me. Now that I haven’t seen her, she must be on the way. Could you call her?” I begged in a shaking voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Of course I can. Look. So many people are waiting for you,” she points to the children and their parents who are sitting side by side on the playground. “You’ll give them today’s best show. Remember how much you like this dance drama and how hard you have practiced?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have nothing to answer. Avoiding the stares cast on me, I walk towards the chair in the corner of the backstage, pass all other performers gathering in the opposite direction, sit down, and bury my face in my arms. Why is she still not here? Is she still working? Does she forget what she promised me? Something named despair is blocking my throat but I won’t cry. Tears will spoil the makeup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gazing at my favorite skirt, I remember the afternoon of last weekend when mom and I were picking the dress for performance at Wuhan Square. She tell me with an amazed look when I came out from the fitting room, wearing the white skirt, “You are my angel!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mom, please be my angel and come to save me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that what she expects to see? I must be the only one feeling depressed in this room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that what I want? I am ruining the whole performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I become the focus of teachers and performers because they are waiting for me; they are now all watching me, because I set them on edge. I don’t feel good about having others wait with me; I know what it feels like to wait after all. Poor Jin. Just a couple of minutes ago she laughed so happily. Now I dare not see her face. How easy it is to destroy other’s happiness! Ms. Chen’s patience must be wearing thin. Feeling disappointed for my mother and guilty for other performers including Jin, I am already out of breath. I raise my head a little for a gasp. At this moment, I see Jin’s worried face. I don’t even know when she come to sit here. I look around and I see others: They are all sitting beside me. I begin to be aware that the performance today is not my own self-satisfying show. Instead of swallowing the groans alone in the corner, I can do something nicer for these people. The performance is not over. It just begins. “Tack, tack, tack…” When I just stand up and don’t know what to say, I heard Ms. Chen’s footstep towards here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yaqi, see who is coming!” Ms. Chen says delightfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look up and see my mom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;*                 *                 *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day finally became one of my happiest days, with my mother getting to the kindergarten in time and we performing as planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why were you so late?” I asked on the way she walked me back after the performance, “I thought you were not coming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I told you I would be there, a little late but I would make it before your show time yesterday. My working hour is 7:00 to 12:00. Baby you were not listening, right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, did you say that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, I did. You need to listen more carefully.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I will learn to listen.” I laughed and shrugged.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Life"></category><category term="Childish Story"></category><category term="Coming-of-Age"></category><category term="Personal Narrative"></category><category term="Writing Practice"></category></entry></feed>